Guide to the Daisy Aldan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Daisy Aldan papers
1919-2000
YCAL MSS 613
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
73.58
(104 boxes) + 3 portfolios, 4 broadside folders, 5 art storage objects
The Daisy Aldan Papers document the work of poet, editor, educator, translator, and filmmaker Daisy Aldan. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, writings of others, notebooks, diaries, teaching material, artwork, audiovisual material, photographs, printed material, and personal papers spanning the years 1919 to 2000.
Aldan, Daisy
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Daisy Aldan, 1983-2000. Gift of Diana Cohen, 1992. Purchased from the Argosy Book Store on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 1999. Purchased from Charles Apfelbaum on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 31-32, 35-36, 106-110 and 116 (sound and video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 94-97 (motion picture film): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 33-34, 98-105 and 115 (reel-to-reel sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Daisy Aldan (1923-2001)
Daisy Aldan, American poet, editor, educator, translator, and filmmaker.
Aldan was born in 1923 in New York City to designer Louis Aldan and actress Esther Edelheit Aldan. She was a child actor on the CBS radio program, Let's Pretend, and was first published in the pages of Poetry at age twelve. Aldan stayed in New York City, where she received a Bachelor of Arts from Hunter College in 1943, a Master of Arts from Brooklyn College in 1948, and took graduate coursework at New York University. Her publications included her first chapbook of poems (1946), The Destruction of Cathedrals and Other Poems (1963) and Seven: Seven (Poems and Photographs) (1965) and several books of experimental poetry published in the 1970s. In 1979, with the assistance of a National Endowment for the Arts grant, she published the novella, A Golden Story.
Aldan co-founded, with Richard Miller, the Tiber Press in 1953 and published and edited Folder Magazine of Literature and Art (1953 to 1959), an influential magazine featuring the poetry of New York School poets and the art of many notable artists. In 1959, she published the anthology A New Folder: Americans: Poems and Drawings. Aldan also co-edited, with Anaïs Nin, the poetry magazine Two Cities (1961 to 1962).
Throughout her career, Aldan contributed to many anthologies and literature magazines. She was a respected translator and published translations of works by Stéphane Mallarmé, Anaïs Nin, Albert Steffen, and Rudolf Steiner. In 1955 she made the 8mm color film, Once Upon an El, that featured several notable artists, writers, and composers protesting the demolition of New York City's Third Avenue elevated railway. For thirty-five years, Aldan taught at the School of Industrial Art (presently the High School of Art and Design) in New York City, where her students included Gerard Malanga, Jackie Curtis, Art Spiegelman, Tony Bennett, Calvin Klein, and Harvey Fierstein. Her former students cite her as a major influence in their identity and evolution as artists. Aldan died in New York City in 2001.
Scope and Contents
The Daisy Aldan Papers document the professional and personal life of poet, editor, educator, translator, and filmmaker Daisy Aldan. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, writings of others, notebooks, diaries, teaching material, artwork, audiovisual material, photographs, printed material, and personal papers spanning the years 1919 to 2000.
Arrangement
Organized into twenty groupings: I. August 1983 Acquisition. II. April 1989 Acquisition. III. April 1990 Acquisition. IV. July 1990 Acquisition. V. July 1990 Acquisition. VI. February 1991 Acquisition. VII. July 1992 Acquisition. VII. November 1992 Acquisition. VIII. November 1992 Acquisition. IX. November 1992 Acquisition. X. November 1992 Acquisition. XI. May 1993 Acquisition. XII. June 1993 Acquisition. XIII. May 1995 Acquisition. XIV. December 1995 Acquisition. XV. November 1997 Acquisition. XVI. February 1998 Acquisition. XVII. July 1998 Acquisition. XVIII. October 1999 Acquisitions. XIX. December 2000 Acquisition. XX. June 2005 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in all twenty groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Editors, American -- 20th Century; Translators, American -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiocassettes; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs -- 20th Century; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings -- 20th Century; Videocassettes; Authors; Editors; Lecturers; Translators; Women authors; Aldan, Daisy
- August 1983 Acquisition, 1959-1980; Series I; 0.63; (2 boxes) + 1 portfolio; 0.63 linear feet (2 boxes, 1 portfolio)
  General note
  Former call number: Uncat ZA Aldan.
  Arrangement
  This material is organized under four headings: Correspondence, Writings, Photographs, and Printed Material.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains correspondence, writing drafts and related material, photographs, and printed material. Includes drafts of and printed material relating to Aldan's novella, A Golden Story; galley proofs of The Destruction of Cathedrals and Other Poems; photographs for A New Folder: Americans: Poems and Drawings, edited by Aldan; and printed material on various topics.
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted letters, 1977-1980, undated (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - A Golden Story, undated
      - "Copy 1" after original journal notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 1)
      - Original version, typescript, undated (Box 1)
      - First version, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 1)
      - Second version, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 1)
      - "Massage: A Golden Story," copy II or III of journal notes, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 1)
      - "Massage: A Golden Story," 4th revision, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 1)
      - Copy returned by Saul Bellow, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 1)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Reception invitation designed by Diana Cohen, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Cover and format design by Diana Cohen, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Reviews, 1979 (Box 2)
    - The Destruction of Cathedrals and Other Poems, galley proofs, 1963 (Box 3 (Portfolio))
  - Photographs
    - Photographs for A New Folder: Americans: Poems and Drawings, edited by Daisy Aldan, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Printed Material
    - Anthropological Society in America Newsletter, 1979 (Box 2)
    - A Golden Story advertisements, circa 1979 (Box 2)
    - A Golden Story cover, with photocopies, circa 1979 (Box 2)
    - A Golden Story reception invitation, 1979 (Box 2)
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] Barone, Dennis. "Daisy Aldan: An Interview on Folder," printed version photocopy (Box 2)
    - Reviews and comments, photocopies, circa 1979 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, undated (Box 2)
- April 1989 Acquisition, 1950-1989; Series II; 2; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 100.
  Arranged under two headings: Literary Correspondence and Printed Material.
  Contains correspondence relating to Aldan's writings, her editing and translation work, and the writings of others; and printed material, including an interview and poetry of others.
  - Literary Correspondence
    - Balakian, Nona, 1964-1981 (Box 4)
    - Benedict, Dianne, 1974-1979 (Box 4)
    - Blaine, Nell, 1958-1968, undated (Box 4)
    - Broughton, James, 1955-1960, undated (Box 4)
    - De Hirsch, Storm, 1962-1965, undated (Box 4)
    - Dlugoszewski, Lucia, 1959-1964, undated (Box 4)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Elmslie, Kenwood, 1958-1969, undated (Box 4)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, undated (Box 4)
    - Harris, Gertrude, 1959-1967, undated (Box 4)
    - Hirschman, Jack, 1959-1971 (Box 4)
    - Holt, Rochelle, 1971-1985 (Box 4)
    - Jacobs, Harriet and the High School of Art and Design, 1963-1974 (Box 4)
    - Koch, Kenneth, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Randall, Margaret, 1963, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Schechter, Ruth Lisa, 1970-1987 (Box 4)
    - Walter, Eugene, 1953-1955, undated (Box 4)
    - Weaver, William Fense, 1953-1955, undated (Box 4)
    - Widershein, Marc, 1983-1987, undated (Box 4)
    - Witt-Diamant, Ruth, 1964-1968 (Box 4)
    - York, Ruth Landshof, 1960-1967, undated (Box 4)
    - Zinnes, Harriet, 1954-1976, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - Individual authors connected with Folder Signatures, 1954-1976, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and other materials connected with Folder Editions, 1953-1976, undated; 2 (Box 4)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1950-1980; 22 (Box 5)
    - Expanding files for literary correspondence, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - Printed material
    - "Saul Bellow: An Interview with Daisy Aldan," printed version and typescript photocopy, 1987, undated (Box 5)
    - Printed poetry volumes, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Unsorted printed ephemera, announcements, etc., circa 1980-1989 (Box 5)
- April 1990 Acquisition, 1989-1990; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 137.
  Arranged under three headings: Writings, Writings of Others, and Other Papers.
  Contains writings by Aldan, cartoon by Diana Cohen, a translation by Aldan, a scrapbook of the exhibition, Folder Editions Exhibition, and a printed announcement for a literary event.
  Custodial History
  Gift of Diana Cohen, 1992.
  - Writings
    - The Annihilation of the Cathares: 13th Century Holocaust. New York: Folder Editions, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Day of the Wounded Eagle, uncorrected galleys, 1990 (Box 6)
    - "Psyche and Eros: Path of Reconciliation of the Eternal Feminine/Masculine/Human," typescript photocopy, undated (Box 6)
    - "Walt Whitman: Poet of the Sublime," typescript photocopy, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Essays, typescript photocopy, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Writings of Others
    - Cohen, Diana. A cartoon inscribed to Daisy Aldan, undated (Box 6)
    - Steffan, Albert. "Barrabas; Drama in Four Acts," translated from German by Daisy Aldan, typescript photocopy, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Other Papers
    - Folder Editions Exhibition: scrapbook containing printed material and photographs, 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Daisy Aldan and Geronimo Sands: Shakespeare and the Evolution of Consciousness: A Dramatic Reading with Commentary," printed announcement (3 copies), 1990 February 16 (Box 6)
- July 1990 Acquisition, 1930-1990; Series IV; 2; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 244.
  - Mallarmé, Stéphane. To Purify the Words of the Tribe: Complete Major Verse Poems, translated by Daisy Aldan, typescript and printed version photocopy, 1990; 2 (Box 7)
  - "The Art and Craft of Poetry," original draft, typescript, 1980 (Box 7)
  - "Durchbruch," German translation of "Breakthrough," by Ingeborg Maresca, typescript, undated (Box 7)
  - Out of the Darkness: Poems by Daisy Aldan, typescript, circa 1930-1940 (Box 7)
  - "Some Articles, lectures and essays by Daisy Aldan," typescript, 1987-1989; 4 (Box 7)
  - "Some Book Reviews, various drafts," photocopies, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - "Some Poems: Complete and Incomplete, 1933-1949," typescript photocopy, undated (Box 7)
  - "Some Short Stories," typescript and typescript photocopy, 1936-1956, undated (Box 7)
  - "Some Poems Written to Daisy Aldan," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1979-1987, undated (Box 7)
  - "Some Worksheets of Daisy Aldan," autograph manuscript and typescript, signed, circa 1975-1990; 4 (Box 7)
  - "Chartres," printed version, signed; and [Five Poems], printed version, 1974, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous poems, typescript and autograph manuscript, 1978-1981, undated (Box 7)
  - "Collected Poems of Daisy Aldan, 1930-1992" typescript, signed, undated; 3 (Box 7)
  - Empty binders, undated; 3 (Box 8)
- July 1990 Acquisition, Series V
  Former call number: Uncat ZA File 251.
  - Obliques, Arcs and Counterpoints, corrected proof; with assorted printed material, 1990 (Box 9)
- February 1991 Acquisition, 1990; Series VI
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 82.
  - Folder Editions Exhibition at Small Press Center, New York, scrapbook with printed material and photographs, 1990 October (Box 9)
- July 1992 Acquisition, 1973-1991; Series VII
  Former call number: Uncat ZA File 283.
  - Cohen, Diana. Twelve portraits of Daisy Aldan, photocopies, signed, 1973-1991 (Box 9)
- November 1992 Acquisition, Series VIII
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 269.
  - Writings, including "The Influence of French Surrealism on American Poetry," translation by Daisy Aldan, typescript photocopy, 1992 September - October (Box 9)
- November 1992 Acquisition, undated; Series IX; 0.63; (2 boxes) + 1 portfolio
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 604.
  - Unsorted writings by Daisy Aldan, with assorted printed material, undated; 13 (Box 10)
  - Unsorted writings by Daisy Aldan, with assorted printed material and photographs, undated; 8 (Box 11)
  - Poems by Daisy Aldan, cover layout; Folder Editions certificate; and Poetry and Eurythmy poster, undated (Box 12 (Portfolio))
- November 1992 Acquisition, 1919-1991; Series X; 10.58; (11 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 273.
  Contains unsorted writings, correspondence, books, and Verses of the Zodiac book cover and group photograph.
  - Unsorted manuscripts, galleys, and correspondence, circa 1950-1990; 26 (Box 13)
  - Unsorted manuscripts, galleys, and correspondence, circa 1950-1990; 10 (Box 14)
  - Unsorted manuscripts, correspondence, and photographs, circa 1950-1990; 10 (Box 15)
  - Unsorted manuscripts and galleys, circa 1950-1990; 13 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, circa 1958-1981; 22 (Box 17)
  - Books, circa 1947-1989; (34 volumes) (Box 18)
  - Books and reprints, circa 1925-1990; (40 volumes) (Box 19)
  - Books, circa 1954-1989; (50 volumes) (Box 20)
  - Books, circa 1925-1991; (55 volumes) (Box 21)
  - Books, circa 1919-1980; (27 volumes) (Box 22)
  - Unsorted galleys, circa 1955-1990; 8 (Box 23 (Oversize))
  - Verses of the Zodiac book cover and group photograph, 1954, undated (Box 23 (Oversize))
- May 1993 Acquisition, Series XI; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 289.
  - To Purify the Words of the Tribe: Complete Poems of Stéphane Mallarmé, Introduction, typescript, 1993 (Box 24)
  - Book reviews and printed material, 1993 (Box 24)
  - Printed material, 1993 (Box 24)
- June 1993 Acquisition, Series XII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA MS 288.
  - "Inspired by... A House Aflame, by Daisy Aldan," student responses, binder, 1993 (Box 25)
- May 1995 Acquisition, 1960-1993; Series XIII; 0.22; (1 box) + 1 portfolio
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA MS 440.
  - Unsorted material including correspondence, manuscripts, photographs and printed material. Includes poems by Daisy Aldan set to music by various composers, including Ann Lipson and J. Schwabenland, circa 1960-1993; 9 (Box 26)
  - Poems of Daisy Aldan set to music by Anthony Tafts, 1981 (Box 27 (Portfolio))
- December 1995 Acquisition, Series XIV; 0.21; (1 box)
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA File 347.
  - Some poems and an essay by Daisy Aldan, typescript, 1995 (Box 28)
- November 1997 Acquisition, 1960-1990; Series XV; 2.96; (8 boxes)
  Contains unsorted correspondence, writings, photographs, and printed material; a photograph and award; and audiovisual material.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 31-32, 35-36: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 33-34: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA MS 539.
  - Unsorted material containing primarily correspondence, with some manuscripts, photographs and printed material, circa 1960-1995; 9 (Box 29)
  - Photograph of Frank O'Hara, Daisy Aldan, and Larry Rivers, 1961 (Box 30)
  - Agate Educator Recognition Award, 1990 (Box 30)
  - Audiocassettes (16 tapes) (Box 31)
    Box 31: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiocassettes (5 tapes) (Box 32)
    Box 32: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Reel-to-reel audio tapes (7 tapes), 1963-1980 (Box 33)
    Box 33: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Reel-to-reel audio tapes (4 tapes), 1956-1978 (Box 34)
    Box 34: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Video recordings (Box 35)
    Boxes 35: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Let's Pretend Reunion (10.31.95)" by The Museum of Television and Radio Seminar Series, 1996 January 29; YCALMSS613_0001; 1; 01:20:13 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002102300283)
      Accompanied by a note from Maria T. Pagano of The Museum of Television and Radio extending her regrets that Aldan's health prevented her from participating in the series, dated 1996 January 29
      According to the label, the tape is dated 1995-10-31.
    - "Daisy Aldan-Shakespeare 1991; Priscilla Beach Theatre 1988", circa 1990; YCALMSS613_0002; 1; 01:40:13 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002102300291)
    - Rehearsal, interview and reading, Daisy Aldan at the Living Theatre with Geronimo Sands interview by Dorothy Friedman, 1991 March 3; YCALMSS613_0003; 1; 03:18:27 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002102300309)
  - Sound discs (7 records), 1966-1970, undated (Box 36 (Record Album Storage))
    Box 36: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- February 1998 Acquisition, 1995; Series XVI; 0.21; (1 box)
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA MS 551.
  - Unsorted manuscripts, correspondence, and personal papers, circa 1995; 9 (Box 37)
- July 1998 Acquisition, Series XVII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA MS 561.
  - Unsorted manuscripts, circa 1998; 4 (Box 38)
- October 1999 Acquisitions, 1960-1976; Series XVIII; 1.25; (2 boxes)
  Contains correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs, and printed material relating to Anaïs Nin.
  Fomer call number: Uncat ZA MS 639.
  Purchased from the Argosy Book Store on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 1999.
  - Correspondence with Anaïs Nin, 1960-1976; 17 (Box 39)
  - Unsorted manuscripts, printed material, and correspondence relating to Anaïs Nin, undated; 5 (Box 39)
  - Photograph album and loose photographs relating to Anaïs Nin, 1960s-1970s; 4 (Box 39)
  - Broadside advertisement for The Diary of Anaïs Nin: 1931-1934, undated (Box 40)
- December 2000 Acquisition, 1940-1989; Series XIX; 50; (64 boxes) + 4 broadside folders, 5 art objects
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 95.
  Organized under four headings: Correspondence, Writings, Other Papers, and Audiovisual Materials.
  Contains correspondence with various individuals, including Diana Cohen, Gerard Malanga, and Elaine Upton. Printed material, notes, clippings and lists that were among the correspondence were removed and are filed at the end of the correspondence. Writings include various drafts of poems and other writings by Aldan; written interviews conducted by Aldan with Anaïs Nin, Arthur Adamov, and Robert McDermott; lectures on Raoul Ratnowski and Stéphane Mallarmé; the typescript for Aldan's film Once Upon an El; Aldan's translations of others' writing into English; notebooks and diaries; and writings of others, including Diana Cohen, Albert Steffen, and poems by Aldan's students. Other writings included unsorted and unidentified writings that include book reviews, notes, poems, research material on Anaïs Nin and Stéphane Mallarmé, school papers, and short stories.
  Other papers include personal papers, photographs of various individuals and events, printed material, and artwork and objects owned by Aldan. Audiovisual material consists of film, sound recordings and video recordings. Film includes the original 8mm color film of Aldan's Once Upon an El, and various 8mm and 16mm reels. Sound recordings are reel-to-reel tapes, including the original sound elements of Once Upon an El, audiocassettes, and record albums. Sound recordings primarily contain various readings, radio programs, and music. Video recordings include VHS, Betamax, and U-matic tapes.
  Boxes 94-105 (motion picture film and sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 106-108, and110 (sound and video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence
    - Cohen, Diana, 3 (Box 41)
    - Finfer, Esther (Box 41)
    - Hacklandes, Ili, 3 (Box 41)
    - Malanga, Gerard, 6 (Box 41)
    - Pennant, Edmund, 2 (Box 41)
    - Rippman, Ernst (Box 41)
    - Upton, Elaine, 5 (Box 42)
    - Unsorted, 10 (Box 42)
    - Printed Material (Box 42)
    - Notes and Newspaper Clippings (Box 42)
    - Lists of Books, etc. (Box 42)
  - Writings
    - Writings by Aldan
      Arranged alphabetically by title of work.
      - The Annihilation of the Cathars, 2 (Box 43)
      - The Art and Craft of Poetry, 4 (Box 43)
      - "The Baker of Sugar Loaf Hill", 4 (Box 43)
      - Between High Tides (Box 43)
      - "Biography", 2 (Box 43)
      - "Blood and Snow", 2 (Box 43)
      - Breakthrough, 8 (Box 44)
      - Collected Poems, 11 (Box 44)
      - "Contemplations for Yasuko" (Box 45)
      - "Contemporary Poetry Paste-ups" (Box 45)
      - "Daisy Alden and Anaïs Nin: Memoir from a Journal" (Box 45)
      - Day of the Wounded Eagle, 17 (Box 45)
      - Day of the Wounded Eagle, 15 (Box 46)
      - The Destruction of Cathedrals and Other Poems, 3 (Box 46)
      - "Dirty Dave" (Box 46)
      - "Eurythmy Exercises" (Box 46)
      - "Everything Notes Durnach" (Box 46)
      - "French Poets of the Forties" (Box 47)
      - "Gabriel" (Box 47)
      - "Gabriella", 4 (Box 47)
      - A Golden Story, 12 (Box 47)
      - A Golden Story, 6 (Box 48)
      - In Passage, 3 (Box 48)
      - "The Influence of French Surrealism on American Literature", 2 (Box 48)
      - Interviews with Anaïs Nin (Box 48)
      - Interview of Arthur Adamov (Box 48)
      - Interview of Robert McDermott (Box 48)
      - "The Irish Theater" (Box 48)
      - Journey (Box 49)
      - "Karoline" (Box 49)
      - Lecture about Raoul Ratnowski (Box 49)
      - Lecture and reading Stéphane Mallarmé (Box 49)
      - "The Little Mermaid: A Radio Play" (Box 49)
      - "Look Down, New York" (Box 49)
      - "Love Was" (Box 49)
      - "Mathilde Blind", 8 (Box 49)
      - "Mexican Interlude" (Box 49)
      - "The Mission of Poetry" (Box 49)
      - "Movement and Form in the Graphic Art of Rudolph Steiner" (Box 49)
      - "N is the Sign of Pisces" (Box 49)
      - "New Poems" (Box 49)